<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Beccalia Development Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[This blog contains development updates for the Beccalia series of games.]]></description><link>https://blog.beccalia.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 19:37:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Beccalia Origins - Planning Update]]></title><description><![CDATA[It’s taken us much longer than we had originally anticipated, but we’ve finally completed the initial planning stage for Origins! This means…]]></description><link>https://blog.beccalia.com/origins/planning-complete/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.beccalia.com/origins/planning-complete/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It’s taken us much longer than we had originally anticipated, but we’ve finally completed the initial planning stage for Origins! This means we’ve mapped out the story line, characters, enemies, skills, items, locations, and quests. It’s a lot of information in a lot of tables, but our hope is that this streamlines the development process significantly - and results in a cleaner and tighter game build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there’s still much planning which will be done on the fly (for example, we haven’t planned any side quests as those will be added throughout the build process). However, the bulk of the information is now at least &lt;em&gt;on paper&lt;/em&gt;, so to speak. These notes are, of course, available to sponsors on our development site - so if you haven’t sponsored us yet, this is a good time to do so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hope is to begin the actual development, starting with loading all of this information into the game database and designing the various maps. We will continue to provide updates both here and on our Twitter account, so give us a follow if you’d like to stay in the loop! For those who are curious, we added about 580 lines of data - which feels like a lot, compared to the scale of our previous games! We thank you for your patience as we continue this process - we intend to deliver the best product possible, even if that takes time.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Beccalia Origins - Outline Update]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hey friends! It’s been a while since our last update, and we do apologise for that. However, we have some good news to share today! We have…]]></description><link>https://blog.beccalia.com/origins/outline-complete/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.beccalia.com/origins/outline-complete/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hey friends! It’s been a while since our last update, and we do apologise for that. However, we have some good news to share today! We have finally completed the story outline for our next Beccalia instalment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beccalia: Origins will tell the story of how Becca and Rosalia came into adulthood. You’ll get to see their childhood, the events that led them to start their paths of adventure, and how they came to learn their skills. You’ll also get to see the moment when they first meet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game will be unique in that you will choose one of two paths to follow: Becca’s or Rosalia’s. That means you’ll need to play the game twice to get the full story, but you’ll essentially get two different games in one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still have quite a bit of work to do before actual development starts. We still need to map out the quests, skill sets, enemy lists, and equipment options. We’re hoping to have this done within a month or so, but we won’t be able to provide any planned release date for a while yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outline, as well as the future information maps described above, are available on our development notes site. This site can be accessed by folks who sponsor us at the Silver tier or higher. If you’re interested in gaining access, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;sponsors page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you again for your patience! We look forward to providing the next update!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Beccalia Prologue - Release!]]></title><description><![CDATA[After 140 hours of development time spanning six weeks, we are very excited to announce the launch of our first game - Prologue. This game…]]></description><link>https://blog.beccalia.com/prologue/release-announcement/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.beccalia.com/prologue/release-announcement/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;After 140 hours of development time spanning six weeks, we are very excited to announce the launch of our first game - &lt;strong&gt;Prologue&lt;/strong&gt;. This game will give you a brief introduction to our series’ two main characters, Becca and Rosalia. You’ll get a glimpse of who they are and the relationship they have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game has an average playtime of 4-6 hours, during which you’ll encounter a variety of different characters and locations. You’ll be sent on quests, fight all sorts of enemies, and make some new friends along the way. We encourage you to take the time to explore everything; there are a lot of little gems and funny moments scattered throughout the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our first attempt at game development, and we used the RPG Maker MZ engine. Our wonderful beta testing team have worked with us to ensure this game is as bug-free as possible, but if you happen to run in to something that doesn’t seem right, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;join our support server&lt;/a&gt; and let us know! We’ll be staying on top of bug reports and pushing updates/fixes as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you love the game (we hope you will!), don’t forget you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://nhcarrigan.com/sponsor&quot;&gt;make a donation&lt;/a&gt;, which will help us fund the next game (the next one will be a much longer game!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get &lt;a href=&quot;https://nhcarrigan.itch.io/beccalia-prologue&quot;&gt;Beccalia: Prologue&lt;/a&gt; on the itch.io website.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Announcing Our New Blog!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Welcome to the Beccalia Development Blog! We will be using this blog site to share the latest news and development updates regarding our…]]></description><link>https://blog.beccalia.com/social/welcome/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.beccalia.com/social/welcome/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Beccalia Development Blog! We will be using this blog site to share the latest news and development updates regarding our game series. Our blog offers an RSS feed which you can plug in to your favourite reader, or you can watch the open-source repository on GitHub to ensure you never miss a post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;Join our Chat Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nhcarrigan&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/beccalia/development-blog&quot;&gt;Follow this blog on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.beccalia.com/rss.xml&quot;&gt;RSS Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>